迈克∶动画片!本,这么大年龄了还看动画片?
Mike: Cartoons!Ben, you are watching cartoons at your age?
本∶有什么不行吗?
Ben: What's wrong with that?
迈克∶你说说看,本,
Mike: What's wrong Ben, is that with cable,
我们有有线电视,可以看所有那些女人的斗争的频道.哦,
we have got the all women's wrestling channel.Oh hey, the road runner!
道路奔跑者!我的最爱.
My favorite.
麦琪∶也许你根本就没有带钱包.
Maggie: Maybe you didn't take your wallet with you.
杰森∶麦琪,我肯定我带了.
Jason: Maggie, I know I had it with me.
当我在美容院和那个女人聊天时,我都感觉了到鼓鼓的钱包呢.
I could feel my bulge when I was talking to the woman in cosmetics.
我要告诉你的是,我的钱包被偷了.
I'm telling you.Somebody lifted my wallet.
迈克∶他们割断了你钩在钱包上的链子?
Mike: You mean they cut the chain that you had hooked to it?
杰森∶我只这样做过一次.就是玩水橇的那次,你是不是要一直提醒我这件事情.
Jason: I did that once.One time water skiing and you won't let me forget it.
电视:一二三,一二三.
TV: One two three, one two three.Think how happy he will be.
想想他多高兴.女孩们,再来五十个.
Ok girls, fifty more.
开萝尔:50!
Carol: Fifty!
电视:由于你的抱怨,60个.
TV :Since you whined, sixty.
开萝尔∶没有哪个男人值得动力蹲伏.
Carol: No man is worth power squats.
麦琪∶开萝尔,你没有看见你爸爸你的钱包吧?有吗?
Maggie: Carol, you haven't seen your dads wallet, have you?
开萝尔∶没有.你问迈克了吗?
Carol: No.Did you frisk mike?
麦琪∶有一个想法.开萝尔..
Maggie: That's a thought.Carol...
开萝尔∶是的.
Carol: Yeah.
麦琪∶没有哪个男人值得蹲伏.
Maggie: No man is worth power squats.
开萝尔∶跳动灵活的守门员?
Carol: Jumping jacks?
麦琪∶或许.
Maggie: Maybe.
开萝尔∶1 2 3 4 5,哈哈!
Carol: And one and two and three and four and five and ahhhhhh!
我要拿一个比例尺来,证明不是我的错.
I'll get on a scale and prove this wasn't my fault.
杰森∶那么你们的电视广告又是什么意思,索赔理算人在事情还没解决前就在那里开支票?你在嘲笑什么?听着,伙计,我要告诉你的是我的女儿刚刚从天花板上滑下来,并且她已经受伤了.不,她只是个小孩.哈罗.
Jason: Alright, well then how come in your TV commercials, the claims adjuster is there writing a cheque before the dust even settles?What are you laughing at?Look pal, I'm telling you my daughter just came crashing through the ceiling.She could have been hurt.No she's not a large girl.Hello.
麦琪∶杰森,当你从机械上购买保险的时候,你就不要指望有任何的服务.
Maggie: Jason, don't expect service when you buy insurance out of a machine.
杰森∶我从一个有棚的货车上买的这张保险单.
Jason: I bought that policy from a guy in a van.
他还跟我出示了商业名片和所有的证件.
He had business cards and everything.
劳埃德∶好,我已经检查过整个房间了.
Lloyd: Ok folks.I checked the whole house.
麦琪∶有没有发现什么,库明斯先生?
Maggie: Well what exactly did you find Mr.Cummings?
劳埃德∶叫我劳埃德.
Lloyd: Call me Lloyd.
杰森∶好,劳埃德...
Jason: Ok Lloyd, well...
劳埃德∶我要她叫我劳埃德,而不是你.
Lloyd: I told her to call me Lloyd, not you.
杰森∶库明斯先生...
Jason: Ok, Mr.Cummings...
劳埃德∶你可以叫我巴里
Lloyd: You can call me Barry
杰森∶巴里,拉里,
Jason: Barry, Larry, whoever the hell you are.
不管你是谁.我们的天花板上怎么会有一个洞?
Why have we got a whole in the ceiling?
劳埃德∶白蚁.
Lloyd: Termites.
开萝尔∶我告诉过你不是我.
Carol: I told you it wasn't me.
杰森∶开萝尔,离那个洞远点,
Jason: carol, please get away from the whole or the whole thing could
否则所有的东西都可能会掉下来的.
come down.
开萝尔∶哦!好爸爸.谢谢.
Carol: Oh nice dad.Thanks.
劳埃德∶如果你需要害虫驱除人,我可以推荐.
Lloyd: If you need an exterminator, I have someone I can recommend.
麦琪∶但是,就是你.
Maggie: But, but this is you.
劳埃德∶天啊它是.我能帮你什么呢?
Lloyd: My god it is.How can I help you?
杰森∶但是我以为你是一个受雇做杂事的人.
Jason: But I thought you were a handy man.
劳埃德∶显然,我以前从未为你工作过.
Lloyd: I've obviously never worked for you before.
麦琪∶多少只白蚁呢?
Maggie: So how many termites?
劳埃德∶我希望有很多,因为如果只有一只的话,
Lloyd: Well I hope a lot, because if it's only one,
那我们就要失业了.哈哈哈.
we'd better all run for our lives.Ha ha ha.
开萝尔:等等,
Carol: just for the record,
我比标准体重沉四镑.
I am four pounds lighter than I should be for my height.
麦琪∶开萝尔,没有人认为你是矮胖的.
Maggie: Carol, no one thinks you are chunky.
开萝尔∶白纸黑字.
Carol: Its right here in black and white.
杰森∶稍后我会看.
Jason: I'll read it later.
劳埃德∶我今天可以照看房子,明天喷药,
Lloyd: I could have the place tented today,
你们星期一就可以回来住了.
sprayed tomorrow and you could be back in here by Monday.
杰森∶那要花多少钱?
Jason: What's all this going to cost me?
劳埃德∶很难说.因为是在周末.
Lloyd: well, it's hard to say.But it is the weekend.
杰森∶好,谢谢,我们会打电话给你.
Jason: Alright, thank you.We'll call you.
劳埃德∶是的,是个明智的选择.
Lloyd: Yeah.That's a wise choice.
当白蚁在那里定居的时候,你可以去找一个更便宜的价钱.
You just check on a cheaper price while the termites floss.
麦琪∶杰森,我们为何不让他开始工作?
Maggie: Jason, why don't we just let him get started?
杰森∶麦琪,我对人性的判断都很专业的,
Jason: Maggie, I am a professional judge of human character,
我告诉你的是,
and I'm telling you, this guy Can't be trusted.
这个人不可靠.他在欺骗我们.
There is something about him that's crooked.
麦琪:杰森.
Maggie: Jason.
劳埃德∶抱歉.我在走廊里找到这个钱包.是你的吗?
Lloyd: Excuse me.I found this wallet on the porch.Does it belong to you?
麦琪:你怎么知道的?
Maggie: Well what do you know?
杰森,你的钱包没有被偷,
Jason, your wallet wasn't stolen and not only that,
信用卡和钱都在.
your credit cards are here, and all your money.You were saying sweetheart?
杰森∶多久,你可以,开始噢..?
Jason: So, how soon, uh, could you, uh, start uh...?
劳埃德∶立刻.
Lloyd: Poncho.
杰森∶立刻.
Jason: Poncho.
杰森∶开萝尔,什么东西这么重要又这么重,
Jason: carol, what could possibly be so essential and so heavy that you
让你2天不用都不行?
couldn't live without it for two days?
本∶她的粉刺药膏.
Ben: her pimple plaster.
杰森∶哈罗,我是西维尔医生.我们要预定房间.
Jason: Hello, I'm doctor Seaver.We called ahead for a reservation.
接待员∶是,你需要在房间里附加三张床.
Receptionist: Oh yes, and you needed three additional cots with that room.
麦琪∶床?
Maggie: Cots?
杰森∶我认为让孩子们打地铺是不对的..
Jason: Well I don't think its right for the kids to sleep on the floor.
接待员∶你是一个顽皮的人.
Receptionist: Oh, you're a naughty man.
杰森∶你说什么?
Jason: Pardon me?
接待员∶你试图使用一张挂失的信用卡.
Receptionist: You are trying to use a stolen credit card.
杰森∶不可能.看清楚.
Jason: Oh no.See that.
接待员∶你认为他们被偷了,所以你去挂了失,
Receptionist: You thought they were stolen so you reported them,
找到他们后,又忘记了去收回.
then found them later and forgot to call back.
杰森∶是这样的.
Jason: that's it.
接待员∶女人得到同工同酬.
Receptionist: And women receive equal pay for equal work.
杰森∶等等,等等.不要那么做.你在这里是干什么的.
Jason: Wait wait, don't do that.What are you doing there.
接待员∶这是我们处置像先生你这样的人的办法.
Receptionist: Cos that is how we treat scum buckets like you sir.
杰森∶我想要找你们的经理.
Jason: I want to talk to your manager.
麦琪∶用我的卡,定了房间后再去说.
Maggie: You can do that after you put the room on my card.
杰森∶麦琪,不要那样看着我.
Jason: Maggie, don't look at me like that.I had to call and cancel the cards.
我必须打电话去取消这些卡.一些神经失常的人可以大肆的挥霍.
Some goofball could be on a wild spending spree.
麦琪∶透支额为100美元的信用卡?
Maggie: Oh a card with a hundred dollar limit?
杰森∶250.
Jason: Two fifty.
接待员∶噢哦!!
Receptionist: uh oh!
开萝尔∶噢哦什么?
Carol: Uh oh what?
接待员∶近朱者赤,近墨者黑.
Receptionist: When we lie down with pigs, we come up smelling like garbage.
麦琪∶什么?
Maggie: What?
接待员∶相同的帐号.
Receptionist: Same account number.
麦琪∶我不是骗子.
Maggie: I am not a crook.
接待员∶我们在哪里听说过.
Receptionist: And where have we heard that before.
杰森∶听着,夫人.信用卡没有被偷.这全部是误会.我的孩子们将为我作证.
Jason: Ma'am listen.The credit cards were not stolen.This is all a mistake.My kids will vouch for me.
本∶我不认识这个人.
Ben: I don't know this man.
麦琪∶天奈小姐,
Maggie: Listen Miss uh, miss uh, Tania.
我们的房子正在熏蒸消毒,我们必须找到地方住.
Our house is being fumigated and we have to place to stay.
你能不能接受私人支票?
Can't you just accept a personal check?
接待员∶当然.有效的信用卡.
Receptionist: Oh certainly.With a valid credit card.
麦琪∶我的丈夫是着名的心理学家.杰森显示给她看.
Maggie: Well my husband is a well known psychiatrist.Show her Jason.
杰森∶今天会话到此为止.要一百美元.
Jason: Um, the session is over for today.That will be a hundred dollars.
大家∶啊!
Everyone: Ahhh!
杰森∶相信我.事情都被解决的很好.
Jason: Trust me.This is going to work out fine.
麦琪∶我还是认为冒犯的去打扰你的妈妈和威利不是很好.
Maggie: Well I still think it's wrong to barge in on your mum and Wally
like this.
杰森∶宝贝儿他们有一个极大的公寓.此外他们是我们的家人.
Jason: Honey, they have a huge apartment.Besides they are family.
难道我妈妈会说"对不起,儿子,现在是睡觉时间."
What's my mum going to say, "Sorry son, it's a bad time"?
阿玛∶对不起,儿子,但是是睡觉时间.
Urma: Sorry son, but it's a bad time.
杰森∶妈妈,你总是说你们家随时欢迎我吗?
Jason: Mum, you always said I'd have a home under your roof.
威利∶或许,但是现在是我们的屋顶了.
Wally: Well maybe, but it's our roof now.
阿玛∶这里现在有很多人...
Urma: It's just with all these people now...
麦琪∶阿玛,你们正在开聚会,而没有邀请我们?
Maggie: Urma, you mean you are having a party and you didn't invite us?
威利∶这是一个不同的聚会.哈哈
Wally: Oh, this is a different kind of party.Ha ha.
阿玛∶你们没有人知道的.
Urma: Yes it isn't anyone you know.
威利∶甚至我们也不知道.哈哈.
Wally: It isn't even anyone we know.Ha ha ha.
杰森∶你们在款待你们不认识的人?
Jason: You're entertaining people you don't know?
阿玛∶不要管威利.我们认识他们.
Urma: Don't pay any attention to Wally.Yes we do know them.
杰森∶怎么认识的?
Jason: How?
阿玛∶通过新闻信件.
Urma: Through the news letter.
杰森∶我知道自从你跟那个懒鬼结婚后,他就会拉你下水.
Jason: I knew, I knew as soon as you married that bum he'd drag you down
做一些天晓得的事情,与完全不认识的人开聚会,上帝!
to his level.Doing god knows what with total strangers.Oh god!
威利∶你们和杰丽威尔的影迷俱乐部有什么过节吗?
Wally: What have you got against the Jerry Vale fan club?
本∶嘿,当真是他.
Ben: Hey, it's really him.
阿玛∶威利,你为何不去看看杰丽需要点什么.
Urma: Wally, why don't you see if Jerry needs anything.
威利∶你们去.
Wally: You got it.
开萝尔∶奶奶,我们能到哪里呆到星期一?
Carol: Grandma, where are we supposed to go until Monday?
没有信用卡,没有现金.
We have no credit cards, no cash..
阿玛∶我感觉真的很难过.
Urma: Oh, I feel really bad about this.
杰森∶妈妈,
Jason: Look mum, if we can't stay here,
如果我们不能留下来,或许你可以帮我一点...
maybe you could help me out with a little...
你能不能让孩子们在厅里等一秒钟.
Would you kids wait in the hall please, for a second.
本∶为什么?
Ben: Why?
开萝尔∶本,你没有敏感性吗?
Carol: Ben, don't you have nay sensitivity?
他不希望我们听他乞求他的妈妈给他点钱.
He doesn't want us to hear him begging his mummy for money.
阿玛∶杰森,我很高兴借你一些钱.
Urma: Jason, id be very happy to lend you some money.
麦琪∶谢谢阿玛.
Maggie: Thank you Urma.
阿玛∶和威利谈谈.钱的事情都是他处理的.
Urma: Just talk to Wally.He handles all of that stuff.
杰森∶找威利谈谈!妈妈,你不能做吗?
Jason: Just talk to Wally!Come on mum, can't you do it?
麦琪和奶奶∶哦!杰森,成熟点!
Maggie and Grandma: Oh Jason, grow up!
杰森∶嘿威利.
Jason: Uh hu!Hey Wal.
威利∶你还在这里吗?
Wally: You still here?
杰森∶关于懒鬼,我跟你说对不起.
Jason: Look, I'm sorry about the bum thing.
威利∶如果我没有和你的妈妈结婚,
Wally: Well if I weren't married to your mother,
我会把你从窗口抛出去.
I'd have thrown you out of that window.
杰森∶你总是能找到这些玩笑的讽刺的地方.哈哈
Jason: You are going to find the irony of this pretty amusing.Ha ha ha.
威利∶我们走着瞧.
Wally: We'll see.
杰森∶你知道我们发生的信用卡的事情吗?你可以帮我解脱困境,
Jason: You know with the whole thing with the credit cards caput,
如果你能,你知道我在说什么吗?
you would really help me out if you could, you know,?You know what I'm saying?
威利∶我会很高兴把你介绍给杰丽.
Wally: I'd be happy to introduce you to Jerry.
威利∶它也是.那是杰丽威尔.
Wally: No, no, no.It is too.It is Jerry Vale.No, that's not it.
不,不是.这是会计的威利.
This is its financial Wally.You know?You follow?
威利∶是的.但是我要你说出来.
Wally: Yeah.But I want you to say it.
杰森∶威利,对我来说并不容易.
Jason: Come on Wally, this isn't easy for me.
威利∶杰森,如果你想要借钱,
Wally: Look Jason, if you want to borrow money,
你要做的只是求我.
all you have to do is ask me.
杰森∶别再提了.
Jason: Forget it.
麦琪∶杰森,你爸爸怎么说?
Maggie: Jason, what did he say?
杰森∶他说不行.
Jason: He said no.
杰丽∶抱歉.我刚好听到说你需要一些钱.
Jerry: excuse me.I could help over hearing that you needed some money.
真棘手,伙计.
That's tough pal.
凯特∶迈克,这顿饭真棒.
Kate: Mike, this is a wonderful meal.
迈克∶谢谢.当你做小牛排的时候都是很冒险的.
Mike: Oh thanks.You know it's always risky when you are cooking cabaska.
我总是负责吃完主食,而你就负责甜点,对吗?
You know
I handled the main course, and you were going to handle the dessert.Right
凯特∶对.
Kate: Right.
迈克∶凯特,这个吻真是太美妙了,
Mike: You know Kate, all this kissing is great,
我的心里像吃了蜜一样甜.
but I really had my heart set on a moon pie.
(敲门)
(knock at the door)
杰森∶迈克迈克!
Jason: Mike!Mike!
迈克∶如果我们不出声的话,他会离开.
Mike: Um, look, if we are really quiet he'll go away.
杰森∶你可以不出声,但是我们是不会离开的.迈克!
Jason: You can be as quiet as you want.We're not going away.Mike!
迈克∶爸爸,我有一个客人.
Mike: Dad, I've got a guest.
杰森∶现在你有六个了.
Jason: Well now you've got six.
迈克∶你在开玩笑吧?你不会要留在这里吧?
Mike: Come on.Come on.You guys are kidding, right?You're not going to stay here.You're kidding right?
杰森∶迈克,当我开玩笑的时候,我的鼻孔会张的这么开吗?
Jason: Mike, do my nostrils flare like this when I'm kidding?
迈克∶我以为你们会去住旅馆.
Mike: But I thought you guys were going to a hotel.
麦琪∶我们是去过旅馆了.
Maggie: We did go to a hotel.
本∶他们用枪指着我们.
Ben: Yeah.They pulled a gun on us.
迈克∶爸爸,你就这样进来了吗?
Mike: Dad, do you have any idea what you just walked in to?
杰森∶是我所有的建筑物,只要我愿意,我可以瞬间把房租加倍.
Jason: Yes.A structure which I believe I own which I can double the rent on at a moments notice.
迈克∶只是想确定你还记得.
Mike: Just wanted to make sure you remembered that.
开萝尔∶难道我们要睡在这种垃圾地方?这个地方连猪窝都不如.
Carol: So we're all supposed to sleep in this dump?
我知道你们都是这样想的,
This place isn't fit for a pig.
但是,却没有人说一句话.
I know what you are all thinking, and nobody say a word.
杰森∶我们必须得睡在这里,除非有人能给我们200美元.
Jason: Well we are all sleeping here unless somebody can come up with two hundred dollars.
迈克∶没问题.凯特,
Mike: No problem.No problem.
你那里有197块,对吗?
Uh, Kate, you got a hundred and ninety seven bucks?
凯特∶在我的宿舍还有一些空间,如果有人想...
Kate: Look, I've got some space in my dorm room, so if anybody wants to ...
迈克∶为了大家好,我去.
Mike: Ok, ok, for the good of the family, I'll go.
凯特∶我不是说你,迈克.
Kate: I wasn't talking about you mike.
本:我会跟你一起,凯特.等我吃完香肠.
Ben: I'll be right with you Kate.As soon as I'm done with my sausage.
凯特∶我说的是克莉丝.如果大家认为没有问题的话.
Kate: I was talking about Chrissy.If that's alright with you?
麦琪∶让克莉丝自己决定.宝贝儿,
Maggie: Well let's let Chrissy decide.
你想在迈克的公寓里过夜,
Honey, you want to spend the night in Mike's apartment, or with Aunty Kate?
还是要和凯特阿姨一起?凯特.
Kate.
迈克∶我有一个主意,为什么大家不去凯特家呢,
Mike: Look, I've got an idea,
除了凯特以外?
why doesn't the whole family go over to Kate's house, except Kate?
杰森:不行,迈克.
Jason: No Mike.
迈克∶我们还是让凯特来做决定.
Mike: Come on dad.Shouldn't we let Kate make this decision.
凯特:不行,迈克.
Kate: No Mike.
麦琪∶凯特,这里是她晚上需要的所有东西.宝贝,明天见.Maggie
Maggie: Ok Kate.Here's everything she needs for the night.And sweetheart, I will see you tomorrow.
迈克∶我还有另外一个主意.这些杀虫剂到底会有多么厉害呢?
Mike: Ok, I got one more idea.I mean, how bad can this pesticide really be?
凯特∶当你潦倒的时候,你真聪明.
Kate: You are so cute when you are frustrated.
迈克∶我现在肯定是极端令人满意的.谢谢大家,
Mike: I must be stinking gorgeous right now.
一大群.
Well thank you everyone, a whole bunch.
麦琪∶迈克,我也不想这样.
Maggie: Well Mike, this isn't a barrel of monkeys for me either.
开萝尔∶我也是.
Carol: Or me.
本∶我也是.
Ben: Or me.
麦琪∶杰森,你为什么不能...
Maggie: Jason, why couldn't you have....
杰森∶麦琪,我告诉过你..
Jason: Maggie, I told you...
大家∶(吵架)
Everyone: (Arguing)
迈克∶什么?
Mike: What?
本∶我在香肠里发现了一个头不是发.
Ben: I found a hair in this sausage.
迈克∶不是头发,只是叶脉.
Mike: It's not a hair, it's just a vei n.
杰森∶别吵了,别吵了.我们今天已经过的很艰难了.对,你是大吃一惊,你的信用卡被冻结,你吃到了一个叶脉.杰丽威尔占我的便宜,坐在那里等着有机会跟可爱的小姐聊天.难道我们就这样被这些打倒吗?
Jason: Stop it, stop it, stop stop stop it!Coe on.Ok, we've had a tough day.Yes, you fell through the floor.You had your credit cards cut up.You ate a vein.Jerry Vale dumped on me.sitting here with a...with a chance to have a nice              conversation with a lovely lady.Are we going to let all this stuff get us down?
大家∶是!
Everyone: Yes!
杰森∶还不至于露营.
Jason: Well not this camper.
不,我要充分利用我们有的东西,
No, I'm going to make the best of what we have.,
我要看看那些装着半杯的杯子.
I'm going to look at this glass as being half full and not half empty.
我要看重事情的正面,而不是负面.
I'm going to accentuate the positive and not the negative.
我要去拿柠檬.
I'm going to take me these lemons, and I'm going to make lemonade.
杰森∶还与人没睡着吗?
Jason: Anyone else still awake?
大家∶是!
Everyone: Yes.
迈克∶我怎样能睡着呢?你们占了我的床.
Mike: How can I get to sleep?You guys got my bed.
杰森∶我是为你妈妈好.她现在年事已高了.好了,既然大家都没有睡着,我们为什么不说说话?
Jason: Well I did it for your mother.She's getting on in years.Oh well
Com eon.As long as everyone's awake, why don't we talk
本∶互相?
Ben: You mean to each other?
杰森∶本.家人之间要经常沟通.
Jason: Ben.Families have been known to talk to each other you know.
本∶是的,在电视上.
Ben: Yeah, on TV.
杰森∶那让我们假装我们在电视上.试试吧,开萝尔,你先来.
Jason: Albright.Alright.Let's pretend we're on TV.Give it a try.Come on.Carol, go first.
开萝尔∶那你想要我说什么?
Carol: Ok, what do you want me to say?
杰森∶无论什么对你来说很重要的.你的感觉.
Jason: Whatever's important to you.Whatever you're feeling.
还有你最深刻的担心焦虑.
Whatever weighs heaviest on your mind.
开萝尔∶好吧.一个笑话.为什么没有人相信我已经减掉了33.3磅呢?
Carol: Oh, here we go.Another ft joke.Why can't anybody just accept the fact
that I have lost thirty three and a third pounds
杰森∶我们不从开萝尔开始了.本.
Jason: Ok, we won't start with Carol.Ben.
本:我有一个笑话.
Ben: Well I've got a good joke, if bodily fluids don't offend you.
杰森∶我们不从本开始了.迈克.
Jason: Ok, we won't start with Ben.Mike.
迈克∶在我回到我的床上前,我是任何话都不会说的.
Mike: I'm not saying anything until I get my bed back.
杰森∶我们不从迈克开始了.麦琪.
Jason: Ok, we won't start with Mike.Maggie.
麦琪∶我不感激那个说我年事已高的那句话.
Maggie: I don't appreciate that crack about me getting on in years.
杰森∶好想法.由我开始.你们还记不记得我们上次是什么时候睡在一个房间的?是10年前,在你们露丝阿姨的葬礼上.那时我们都很开心.
Jason: Good idea.I'll start.You guys remember when the last time was we all
spent the night together in one room?Hu hu hu?Remember?it was ten years
ago, and that was at your aunt Rose's funeral.Now that was a fun time
麦琪∶杰森!
Maggie: Jason!
杰森∶麦琪,我不是说葬礼很有趣.我是说我们不得不一起在你博比叔叔的房子里度过一个晚上,你还记得吗?记得我们干什么了吗?我们玩游戏,唱歌.我们侵略了应急干粮,然后把我们自己塞饱,你还记得吗?
Jason: I don't mean the funeral was fun Maggie.I mean the fact that we had to spend the night in your Uncle Bobbies bomb shelter.Do you remember that?Remember what we did?We played games.We sang songs.We invaded the emergency rations and we gorged ourselves.You remember that?
麦琪∶对.
Maggie: Yeah.
杰森∶你的妈妈喝醉酒了,把博比叔叔的应急灯打开了.
Jason: Your mum got all tanked up and set off uncle Bobbie's flares.
麦琪∶我不记得了.
Maggie: I did not.
杰森:我知道你不记得了.我只是想让它更有意思.
Jason: I know you didn't.I made that up just to make this more interesting.
迈克∶爸爸,有重点吗?
Mike: Dad, is there a point to this?
杰森∶是的,迈克.重点就是我们是一家日呢.我们没有想到会全家人都挤在地下室的一个房间里.不通风,还有迈克的脚臭.重点是我们现在这样做了,我们已经做到了最好.我隐约觉得这可能是我们一家人最后一次睡在一个房间里了.
Jason: Yes Mike.The point is we were a family then.You know, we didn't
want to spend the night together, all crowded in one room underground.
With no air
and mikes feet.But the point is we did it and we made the most
of it.And it just occurred to me that maybe this is the last time
we'll spend the night together, alone, in one room
迈克∶你们明天会去住旅馆吗?太好了!
Mike: So you mean you're getting a hotel room tomorrow?Great!
开萝尔∶你说真的?
Carol: You mean it?
杰森∶麦琪,麦琪,孩子们是什么时候开始改变的?∶
Jason: Maggie, Maggie, when did these kids change?
麦琪∶(打鼾)
Maggie: (snoring)
埃迪∶迈克,你可以借我10块吗?
Eddie: You Mikey, can you spare me a ten?
麦琪∶什么?
Maggie: What?Uh?
埃迪∶哦,对不起,我不知道你会和你妈妈睡在一起,嘿迈克尔,发生什么事了?
Eddie: Oh, I'm sorry, I didn't realise you were sleeping with your mother.Ahhhh!Hey Michael, what's happening?
迈克∶你几乎都看见了,埃德.
Mike: Well you are pretty much looking at it Ed.
麦琪∶埃迪,你在这里干什么?
Maggie: Eddie, what are you doing here?
埃迪∶迈克,我只是在想,你可不可以借我10元.
Eddie: Well actually Mike, I was wondering if you could lend me a ten.
迈克∶好.
Mike: Yeah.
杰森∶在四(点钟)早晨?
Jason: At four in the morning?
迈克∶你看,我也只剩下20远了.
Mike: Look, all I've got is a twenty.
埃迪∶行了.
Eddie: That will do.
迈克∶等 等,给我只有3块 ,给他出去乱花居然有20块!
Mike: Wait a minute.For me you had three, for him you've got twenty!
迈克∶他要还给我的.
Mike: Well he pays me back.
埃迪∶谢谢迈克尔.这样真的很温馨.
Eddie: Thank you Michael.You know this is really neat.
我家里的人从来都没有在一房间睡过觉.
My family never sleep all together in the same room.
开萝尔,你越来越漂亮了.
Wow, carol, you're developing quite nicely.
本∶我在地板上睡不着,有东西在我身上爬.
Ben: I can't sleep on this floor.Things are crawling on me.
麦琪∶对不起宝贝儿,爬进来.
Maggie: I'm sorry honey, climb in.
杰森∶哦!
Jason: Oh!
开萝尔∶等等,小赖皮也睡在床上了.
Carol: Wait a second.
而我却要在地板上受苦.别再提了.
The snot ball gets a bed and I have to suffer on the floor!Forget it.
迈克∶等等.暂停!这床是谁的呀?我是床的所有者,你们都睡在上面,而我却要睡地板,没门.让出空地方.
Mike: Hey!Wait a minute.Hold it!Time out!Who owns the bed?I'm the one who owns the bed and you guys are going to sleep in it!I'm supposed to sleep on the floor?No way.Make room.
杰森∶哦!好了.
Jason: Oh come on.
开萝尔∶啊唷!嘿迈克,那是我的脚.
Carol: Ow!Hey mike, that's my foot.
迈克∶对不起...
Mike: Well I'm sorry.
杰森∶谁用手肘顶住了我的背?
Jason: Yes, well who's got their elbow in my back?
麦琪:有人应该剪脚趾盖.
Maggie: Somebody needs to cut their toenails.
杰森∶不能怎么多人睡在这个床上.
Jason: You can't have this many people in this bed.
迈克∶爸爸.不必担心,我的床上曾经一次睡过12个男人.
Mike: Dad, I've had twice as many people in this baby.Don't worry, they were all guys.You know what I mean.
开萝尔∶等等,你尿床了?
Carol: Wait a minute.Did you wet the bed?
本∶没有.我们没有尿床,是床在弄湿我们.
Ben: No.Hey, we're not wetting the bed, the bed is wetting us.
迈克∶什么..
Mike: What the...
大家∶啊!
Everyone: Ahhh!
杰森∶哦!好了.
Jason: Come on.
开萝尔∶我要指出的是,是迈克购买的这个充水床垫.不是苗条而有曲线的开萝尔.
Carol: I'd just like to point out that that it was mike who bought the water bed back.Not Slim Svelte.
杰森∶开萝尔开萝尔,住口.
Jason: carol.Carol, shut up/
麦琪∶哦!
Maggie: Oh nice.The genius who cancels the credit cards,
取消信用卡的天才跟他的女儿说"住嘴".
tells his daughter to shut up!
杰森:我已经把我能做的都做了.
Jason: I did what I had to do.
在这里也好过向威利借钱.
Staying here was a lot better than borrowing money from Wally.
麦琪∶不要这么的自大.他没对你做什么事情.
Maggie: Oh don't act so noble.He did nothing to you.
杰森∶你知道多少呀,我根本就没有问他借.
Jason: Oh yeah.Well it shows how much you know.I didn't even ask him.
麦琪∶什么?
Maggie: What?
杰森∶对的,我很骄傲.
Jason: Yeah, that's right.A man has his pride.
麦琪∶你是说我们不是被迫要在这里,而是你选择的?
Maggie: You mean we weren't forced to stay in this place?You chose it?
杰森∶是我选的.在拒绝他之前,我还以为也许大家住在同一个房间,会比较开心.哈哈
Jason: I chose it.But that was before I so stupidly thought that we might
enjoy a little family fun.ha ha ha
迈克∶你只是要站在那里,还是帮我把床喝光.
Mike: Are you just going to stand there, or are you going to help me drink my bed?
麦琪∶太糟糕了.
Maggie: This is terrible.
杰森∶我现在到底在什么地狱?
Jason: Where the hell am I?
麦琪∶杰森!你为什么会一个人在外面?
Maggie: Jason.What are you doing out here?
杰森∶我不知道,我也很迷惑.
Jason: I don't know.I got confused.I got lost.
我迷路了.我想可能当时正在找楼梯.麦琪∶这个看上去不像一个小门吗?
I thought I was heading for the steps.
00:19:27,400
Maggie: Didn't this look like a pretty small door?